<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
    Usable with FlightGear
    Property of Gerard Robin

-->
<PropertyList>

        <title>Catalina PBY6  Water bomber</title>
        <key>
            <name>d</name>
            <desc>Blister open/close</desc>
        </key>
        <key>
            <name>D</name>
            <desc>water tank doors,  close</desc>
        </key>
        <key>
            <name>s </name>
            <desc>Starter</desc>
        </key>
        <key>
            <name>f</name>
            <desc>Toggle Floats Up/Down</desc>
        </key>
        <key>
            <name>l (like "l"etter) </name>
          <desc>release water over your target (water bombing)</desc>
        </key>
        <key>
             <name>L</name>
            <desc>ask for water loading  when ready </desc>
        </key>
        <key>
            <name>B</name>
            <desc>toggle ON/OFF Brake Parking on ground or ON/OFF Cables/Anchor on water</desc>
        </key>
        <key>
            <name>o</name>
            <desc>act auto control of the engine power for takeoff</desc>
        </key>
        <key>
            <name>O</name>
            <desc>act auto control of the engine power for climb</desc>
        </key>
        <key>
            <name>m</name>
            <desc>act auto control of the engine power for cruise</desc>
        </key>
        <key>
            <name>M</name>
            <desc>unact auto control of the engine power, only manual control</desc>
        </key>
        <text>
			==============EYE CANDY ============
			    If you want to get the best of that model, 
we would recommand to use the Rembrandt features, it  gives real shadows and lights
                              It should not slow your computer.
For instance with a GPU Nvidia  GT 560 TI we are getting 40 frame per second at LFML
==================================================================
                =========================================
                That Model is the Catalina  PBY6 converted to be a water bomber
                It was in use in the south-east of France from 1964 to 1970
                =========================================
                Performance:
                That model is tuned ( altitude, climb and speed ) according to a payload of 10000 lbs, which is the water tank capacity filled up.
               So that the fuel tanks capacity is automatically limited at load water process.
	       
	       The other usage without fire fighter scenario gives the full tanks capacity
	       Don't forguet to fill UP on ground if required.
                =========================================
            START and STOP ROUTINE
            To start the engines we suggest to use 
	    the "Catalina Menu"  Easy Start
           

            To take off
            =>Unlock Brake parking  (shift B)
            =>Push the throttle to maximum
            When speed 70 knots pull the stick
            The aircraft will take off
	    OR 
	    you may use
	    the "Catalina Menu"  Propulsion Control Mode
	    then Click  the TakeOff Power button

            To stop the engines
            =>decrease magneto switch  and electric master switch "off" ( key  name "{")

            WATER BOMBER
            You mays simulate  the filling of the water tank ( 4000 liters)
            when
                =>on the water, you want the floats DOWN  (key"f")
                =>prepare the filling (command key  "L")
                => a speed minimum of 45 kts
                => push gently the elevator, just enough to keep the aircraft sliding in the water
            The filling duration time is 100 sec.
            Control your speed which must be more than 45 kts  (if less it does not fill)
            More is better.
            During the filling,  the aircraft is getting more and more heavy.
            When loaded  the weight of the aircraft is heavier of 4500 kg , remember it at take off, you wants patience, and smooth piloting.
            Before climb, you must get the maximum of speed with the help of the groundeffect, which is your friend.
            After take off, don't forget, you want the floats UP (key"f")

            Now you may simulate a water bombing
                => At a low agl, (let's say 200 ft) and over the target which is supposed to be bombed,
                => release the water (command key 'l" like "l"etter)
            The water can be seen falling down.

            The  aircraft is right now 4500 kg less , it will jump upper in the sky, be prepared for it.
            When empty don't forget to close the water tank doors ( key"D")
            You may again, go back on the sea  and fill again, that process is repeatable as long as you wish it.

        </text>

</PropertyList>